ALEXSON ROY: So our next related sports massage athletic condition is mostly what gymnasts and swimmers get, and that's problems with their latissimus dorsi, which is also known as big swim.
And then you have your teres minor as the little swim.
And they call it big swim, little swim because your latissimus dorsi is all of this right here, all the way up to your scapula.
This whole entire muscle, like, of your lower back all the way up into your scapula, okay?
It's at the bottom part, okay?
And your teres minor connects right in here.
It's a little muscle that kinda attaches right through here, okay?
So this is the big swim, and then this is the little swim.
They have the same point of origin but different points of insertion, but it is truly effective when you kinda do that front stroke, okay?
Or let's say you're a gymnast and you're hanging and you're trying to pull yourself up, something like that.
So once again, everything is away from the spine.
Spine is not really a joint, the joints maybe within, but this is not really a joint.
The thing is you'll want to push it away from the actual spine 'cause this muscle right here along the spine is going to get really tight, and then the latissimus dorsi gets really, really tight because the spine is so tight.
So once again, push it down, push it out, okay?
Push down and then out.
Then maybe repeat that a couple of times until you feel it just gives a little bit.